ESUM BRANDON OBEN

Full Stack Mobile and Web Developer



Buea, Cameroon 0000



+237673452821



esumbrandon074@gmail.com

Solution-driven Web and Mobile Application Developer adept at contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused Web and Mobile Application using React with typescript, React native, GraphQL, Flutter and **provider**. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over 5+ years, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

Skills

- Scrum Framework
- Responsive Design
- Web Technologies: React, GraphQL, Tailwind CSS, NodeJS, TypeScript, Problem-Solving.
- Mobile Technologies: React-native, Dart (Flutter), Kotlin.
- Others: Version control (Git), Node Js, Express.

Work History:

Frontend Developer:

Bridge Labs:

2021-09-2023-11

- Designed, developed, and implemented software applications for website based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.
- Tested programs and databases to identify issues and make necessary modifications.
- Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Translated customer requirements into written use cases.
- Designed intuitive graphical user interfaces to improve user experience.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Developed software for desktop and mobile operating systems.
- Discussed issues with team members to provide resolution and apply best practices.
- Worked with react (for web), react native before we migrated to flutter technologies because of the performance issue of react-native (for mobile)

2020-03 *-*2021 - 06

Full Stack Web Developer:

Bohiko:

- Developed functional databases, applications and servers to support websites on back-end.
- Oversaw and implemented automated build and deployment pipelines.
- Inspected equipment, assessed functionality, and optimized controls.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Developed efficient and maintainable software according to business objectives and needs of clients.
- Used JavaScript, SQL and HTML to develop app-solutions.

• React, GraphQL and Typescript were the primary frameworks used

Education:

- B. Tech in Computer Engineering University of Buea, Cameroon (2022)
 - GPA: 3.06
 - Professional Development Studies: Mobile app dev for booking appointments easily with a hospital from home, year 2021

For Projects, check out my portfolio site:

https://esumbrandon.netlify.app

Languages:

English